Kennedy Osemeke

1 Ilare Street, off Airport Road, Lagos State, Nigeria E-mail: kennedyosemeke@gmail.com Phone No: +2348126065307, +2348030843639

CAREER GOAL

To build a career in Communication Engineering and apply knowledge and experience gained over time to the development of an international organization through valuable contributions to the growth of such an organization while developing personal skills.

BIO DATA:

Date of Birth: 13th September, 1982

Age 32 Years
Country of Birth Nigeria
State of Origin Delta State
Marital Status Single
Language English

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- General Skills: AutoCAD, Matlab, Embedded C Programming, MS Excel, MS Power Point, Opnet.
- SDH, PDH, CISCO Network Design Skills, VLAN, VPN, Firewall, Cryptography, OSPF, MS Project.
- GSM Network Planning Tools: U-Net, genex naster, Transdata, Mapinfo (Site see, Grakiter), Google Earth
- GSM Network Optimization Tools: TEMS, Panorama, Pioneer, Qualcomm Extensible Diagnostic Monitor, Actix, Mapinfo Huawei imanager M2000 and Service Maintenance System.
- Microwave Transmission(Line of Site Tools): Path-Loss, Herald, Google Earth

PROFFESIONAL QUALIFICATIONS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification (2009)
- Institution of Engineering and Technology (MIET)
- Project Management Institute (PMI).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

July, 2012 University of Portsmouth, United Kingdom (IET Academic Partner).

MSc. Communication Systems Engineering (Distinction, and award for best MSc. project 2012).

2001-2006 University of Benin

BEng. Electrical/Electronic Engineering (Second Class Upper Division) Major Courses

- ➤ Power Generation, Transmission and Distribution
- > Telecommunication and Information Technology
- > Electronic Engineering.

1993-1999 College of Education, Demonstration Secondary School (SSCE)

RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Kenix Consulting Limited

Oct 2012 till date

- Responsibility: Project Manager
 - Network Planning and Implementation of Metropolitan Area Network (MAN) for Swift Networks.
 - Planning and implementation of fiber optic connection to business enterprises and residential estates under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
 - Installation of backup UPS power systems for enterprises under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
 - Installation and commissioning of wellhead instrumentation and control systems for Cocacola Nigeria
 - Equipment Shelter Installations for Swift Enterprise Networks
 - Site Survey supervision (RF, Microwave and fiber optic).
 - Site Drawing, Checking and Correcting.
 - Analysis of default parameters (Input Power, FD type and Length, Antenna Gain and BW, RF Antenna Height and Link Budget Balancing.
 - Network Performance analysis and Optimization.
 - Provision of Technical and Non-Technical Solution.

Huaxin Consulting/Huawei Technologies Limited

Dec 2009-Jan 2011

Responsibilities: Team Lead Network Planning/Optimization Engineer (Multilinks NOC)

- Network Planning, Optimization and Resource Parameter Adjustments (at NOC) of Telcom/Multi-Links network.
- Network Monitoring and Fault Isolation using Huawei imanager M2000 and Service Maintenance System.
- Analysis of network performance based on statistical counters, network recordings, Geolocation tools and drive test data.
- Provision of Preventive and Corrective Maintenance Suggestions to Customer.
- Preparation of daily, weekly and monthly Performance Reports with extensive use of MS Word, Excel, Power Point and Access.
- Drive Test, Low level optimization, Engineering Parameter Adjustments and network optimization for GSM 2G, GPRS, EDGE, 3G, CDMA 1X and EVDO (voice and data).
- Planning and preparation of BTS Configuration Script.
- Excellent Leadership and Project Management skills.
- Ability to work with little or no supervision.

Huaxin Consulting/Huawei Technologies Limited (Etisalat Project) July 2008 - Dec 2009 Responsibilities: Project Engineer (RNPO)

- Planning and optimization for 2G, 2.5G and 3G Network for Etisalat.
- Technical Site survey and design for new sites (Power Systems, RF, Microwave and Civil Works) using autoCAD.
- Site Verification (Power, RF and Microwave).
- Microwave Transmission planning.
- Frequency, Neighbor List and LAC planning for Etisalat.
- Coordinate and supervise the activities of optimization and drive test engineers.
- Resolve escalated customer complaints.

- Drive Test, Network tuning, parameter adjustment, low level optimization for 2G and 3G.
- Strong analytical skill and initiatives.
- Good inter-personal and communication skills.

Huaxin Consulting

Jan 2008 - June 2008

• 6 months Telecommunications and Power Systems Engineering training

PROJECTS/ RESEARCH UNDERTAKEN

- ECG Data Compression and transmission for Telemedicine using Embedded C Programming for Micro-Controllers (MSc Project)
- Planning and implementation of fiber optic connection to business enterprises and estates under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
- Installation of backup UPS power systems for enterprises under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
- Equipment Shelter Installations for Swift Enterprise Networks
- Installation of Inverters for Kelsan Insurance brokers offices in Lagos, Ibadan, Abuja, Port Harcourt and Warri.
- Site Audit for 62 sites for Nokia Seimens to Huawei swap sites for Airtel in Eastern Region
- Site selection and Technical Site survey for 72 sites for Visafone Nigeria.
- Drive test and optimization for Multilinks/Telcom for Kano, Kaduna and Warri.
- Drive test SSV for Etisalat for 55 sites in Northern region.
- Technical Site survey for 130 sites for Etisalat Nigeria. Subcontracted by Huaxin Consulting.

HOBBIES/INTEREST:

- Playing chess, scrabble and football.
- Swimming

REFERENCES

Mr. Zhou

MD, Huaxin Consulting Nigeria Limited 27/28 Agodogba Street, Parkview Estate, Ikoyi, Lagos zhougx@hxdi.com +234-1-4620370

Mr Hari Krisna

Huawei Technologies Limited Multilinks /Telcom NMC Project Manager hari@huawei.com +2347029588871

Dr Alan Hewitt

Senior Lecturer
School of Engineering
Anglesea Building, Anglesea Road, Portsmouth,
United Kingdom
Hants, PO1 3DJ
alan.hewitt@port.ac.uk